# Abrar Mahi

Brooklyn, New York, United States ◆ Phone: +1(646)763-4662 ♦ Email: amahi2001@gmail.com ♦ LinkedIn: abrarmahi

#### **SUMMARY**

I have always been fascinated by the intersection of math and technology, and look to apply what I learn in school to real-world situations. In my free time, you will find me studying data structures, volunteering, or learning new concepts in finance and tech. I have 2+ years working in professional environments with a strong understanding of Object-oriented design and Data Structures/ algorithms especially with C/C++, java and Python. In the past I have worked and studied many fields of computer Science such as Machine Learning, iOS development with Swift and front end development.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## FET KITCHEN/ PREY LABS

New York, NY

#### 09/2019 - 03/2020

#### Software Engineer Intern

- Created Frontend solutions for website and website mockups using Figma
- UI/ UX design of the website using JavaScript, HTML5 and CSS
- Chatbot integration with IBM Watson
- interpret recommendation system algorithms for marketing teams
- · Assist in interpreting machine learning algorithms with PyTorch on Python 3 for improved recommendation systems

## ENGAGEWHIZ.COM New York, NY

#### 09/2020 - 01/2021

#### Software Engineer Intern

- Assisted in implementing UI/UX solutions to website portal using TypeScript, CSS, and HTML5 using functional programming
- · Assist with Analysis, Design, Development, Testing and documentation of new software solutions
- Collaborates and communicates with internal and outsourced development partners regarding software applications
  design status, project progress, and issue resolution
- Working through the whole software development life cycle, including prototype development, design, coding, unit testing, integration/system testing and writing technical documents

#### **NYU AI SCHOOL: ADVANCED COHORT**

New York, NY

### 01/2021 - 02/2021

#### Student

- Learned about the statistics, calculus and linear algebra required for machine learning.
- Learned about AI programs using various machine learning models with TensorFlow, NumPy, Matplotlib and Pandas on Python 3: Linear regression, logistical regression, Bayes classification and stochastic gradient descent.
- Implemented following models into dataset and image classification programs.

## CODEPATH IOS New York, NY

## 02/2021 - present

## Student

- Learn iOS app development using Swift programming language on Xcode
- Creating iOS apps such as Flix, Instagram, and Twitter app clones
- Integrating various APIs into Xcode projects such as the Twitter API
- Working with various Swift pods such as Parse and AlamoFire for image and backend integration
- Creating and integrating backends for apps using Back4App
- Working with a team of 4 students to create and showcase a unique iOS app which uses various weather-forecast API's to help the user decide which clothes, cosmetics and/or skincare are best for them in accordance with the weather.

# PROJECT: IOS INSTAGRAM CLONE

- Created an iOS Instagram clone using Swift on Xcode
- Allowed user to sign-up/ login into an account, post images from the camera roll with a caption, and comment on other users' posts
- Used the Alamofire pod to better manage image uploads
- Used Parse pod to better manage sign-in parameters
- Implemented a custom backend to store posts, comments and images using Back4App

## **EDUCATION**

## **CUNY HUNTER COLLEGE**

**BA Computer Science** 

- 2019 2023
- Cumulative GPA: 3.75, Computer Science GPA: 3.81
- Dean's List: Fall 2019 present
- Peter F. Vallone Scholar
- Excelsior Scholarship recipient